

Zaragoza (Spain)



678-154-765



maserasen@gmail.com



sergio-asensio-in



sergio-asensio-cv

Sergio Asensio

Mathematician and Software Analyst Developer with a solid background in web applications development and several programming areas such as: Full Stack Developer (FRONTEND, BACKEND), Web Designer, Web Services Implementation (REST/SOAP), Database Management...

During my 4 years of experience, I have attended multiple projects managed by different technologies such as Java, Angular, Salesforce and NodeJs, both alone as well as member of qualified teams helping me all of them in my professional growth and development.

As a full stack technical analyst, some of my main tasks are: Analysis and implementation of the FRONTEND and BACKEND functionalities in the most simple and efficient way, define the database tables structure as well as the relation between them, establish the code architecture of main project modules in order to take them as referents to develop new ones, support and knowledge transfer to team's software developers...etc.

I am a so persistent person with my objectives and this is precisely the aspect that I like most about my work, I see my day by day as challenges to defeat and the more innovative and challenging they are the more motivated I am.

EDUCATION

2011 - 2016

Bachelor of Mathematics - Zaragoza University

LANGUAGES

Spanish

Mother tongue

Speaking and writting upper-intermediate level

SOFTWARE TOOLS

Java

Spring MVC – Spring Hibernate – Spring Boot – Maven – JSF – JPA – jQuery – AJAX – Javascript – Quarz – Apache Tomcat

Salesforce Angular 7 NodeJS Web Design

Apex – Visualforce – Heroku – Marketing Cloud – Schedule Jobs

Typescript – Npm – Reactive Forms – NgModules – Observables & Promises

Express.js – Nodemon – Babel-Node – Knex.js – Objection.js

HTML – JSP – JSPX – CSS – SCSS – Bootstrap 4 – Font Awesome 4– ChartJS

Web Services
BBDD
ETL
Code Editor
Task Management
Version Control

REST – SOAP

PostgreSQL – Oracle – SQL

Talend

Eclipse – Intellij – Visual Studio Code

Jira

Git - Github - Gitlab - Bitbucket - SVN - CVS

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2019-Present

SOFTWARE ANALYST DEVELOPER - (Grupo Oesia)

 Technical full stack analyst and referent in a residue management project for Aragón government. My main role is focused on the definition and implementation of the architecture and functionalities of the FRONTEND (Angular 7) and BACKEND (Spring Boot -JPA) modules of the project as well as the support and knowledge transfer to team's software developers.

March 2018 – May 2019

SOFTWARE SENIOR DEVELOPER - (Grupo Oesia)

- Technical analysis and development of several Angular (Angular 7) modules and Java REST services (Spring Boot -JPA) that were required within an environmental quality and waste management app.
- Main and only responsible of a final client proyect where I was in charge of the expansion of several functionalities related to Zaragoza's civil service app (PrimeFaces – JSPX - SQL).

February 2017– March 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER - (DxD Applications & IT Solutions)

- Structuring and code management of different Salesforce projects, mainly triggers, visualforces, workflows ,REST service integrations and test classes.
- Diving, integration and publishment in Heroku of a Java SMSes data sending app integrated with NodeJs, Marketing cloud, SFDC and Talend platforms by REST services.
- Main responsible of the development and publishment in Heroku of a NodeJs Web service
 app which purpose was the massive user data sending to a SMSes sending data Company as
 well as the storage of the responses received in PostgresSQL.
- Maintenance and creation of new Angular modules for a car's concessionaire app.

March 2016 - February 2017

SOFTWARE JUNIOR DEVELOPER - (DxD Applications & IT Solutions)

- Assistance to software courses related to the competences: SAP (ABAP modality), Java and Salesforce.
- Participation in several maintenance Salesforce projects where I grew up as code developer and platform admin.

	 Full stack developer in an energy market project to simulate some Salesforce functionalities through a Java Web application. Thanks to this project, I learnt and explored several set of tools such as: Spring MVC, Spring Hibernate, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JSP, Javascript, SQL, REST, AJAX, the study of the Heroku platform and its synchronization with Salesforce and the use of Talend tool for massive data migration (ETL). More information in: https://sergio-asensio-cv.berokuapp.com
COURSES	
March – 2016	SAP Formation Course, AVAP modality
April – 2016	Java Formation Course
11pm 2010	Salesforce Formation Course
April – 2018	Angular 6 Formation Course
PRESENTATIONS	
October – 2016	Salesforce Course Intructor
October – 2017	Java Course Intructor
CERTIFICATIONS	
	Java Standard Edition 6 Programmer Certified Professional (Score: 93%)
PUBLICATIONS	
	Ecuaciones Diferenciales Implícitas y Clasificación de sus Singularidades. (URL: https://zaguan.unizar.es/record/36919/files/TAZ-TFG-2015-4450.pdf)
	(OAD. https://zaguan.umzan.cs/iccoid/30717/incs/1772-11-0-2013-4430.put)